（信(しん)）羌瘣(きょうかい)！
（貂(てん)）誰？
Qiang Lei!
Who's that?
He's a guy who fought in the same Wu as me.
（信）同じ伍(ご)で一緒に戦ったヤツだ
（貂）えっ？
But this person is...
（貂）でも この人…
（信）不思議な技を持ってやがって
メチャクチャ強(つえ)えんだ
He's got some mysterious techniques and he's crazy strong.
でかい相手を10人
一気に倒したんだぜ
He took out ten huge opponents at once!
この人が？
（信）お前 なんで こんなとこに？
This person did...?
What're ya doin' here?
A walk.
（羌瘣）散歩
（信）ウソつけ！
You liar!
（羌瘣）
ちょっと 近くを通りかかってな
I was just in the neighborhood...
and came to tell you something.
ひと言だけ 言いに来た
（信）えっ？
（羌瘣）お前…
そのままじゃ いつか命を落とすぞ
If you keep up with what you've been doing, you're going to end up dead.
えっ…
（羌瘣）じゃあな
See ya.
That's all?!
（信）それだけかよ？
（羌瘣）ああ
（信）待てっつの！ こっちだって
聞きたいことが山ほどあんだよ！
Hold on, dammit!
I've got a whole bunch of stuff I wanna ask, myself!
What?
（羌瘣）何だ？
Th-The other day, uh...
こ… この間… その…
（信）俺の背中に…
When you were... behind me...
（貂）うん？
（信）と… とにかく お前…
Anyhow, you're...
a woman, aren't you?
女だろう
（羌瘣）ああ　それが どうした？
（信･貂）えっ？
Yeah. So what?
Why's a woman fighting together with a bunch of men?!
（信）なんで
女が男に交じって戦ってんだ？
None of your business.
お前には関係ない
（貂）待てよ！
Hang on!
は… 腹減ってんじゃないのか？
You must be hungry.
俺が何か作るから 食ってけ
（信）ヘヘッ…
I'll whip something up for you, so come eat with us!
（羌瘣）その必要は…
（おなかの鳴る音）
There is no need for...
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
Ancient China.
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the State of Qin in the far West.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦(しん)から―
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
G_I_A
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Night Tale
（貂）さあ 好きなだけ食べな
（信）食おうぜ
Now then, eat all you want.
Let's chow down!
うまっ！
Yum!
こんなヤツでも 男に交じって…
Somebody like this was living among a bunch of men?
つうか お前 こんな かわいいのに
女って分かんなかったのかよ？
By the way, how the hell'd you not realize she was a woman when she's this cute?
こいつは ずっと顔 隠してたんだ
気づくわけねえだろう！
She had her face covered the whole time!
There was no way I'd notice!
（貂）き… 聞いていいか？
（羌瘣）何だ？
C-Can I ask something?
What is it?
（貂）
“それが どうした”って何だよ？
Why would you say "So what?"?
そんな軽いことじゃねえだろう
That's a pretty big deal!
A woman pretending to be a man...!
女が
男のフリをして生きるってことは
What're you biting her head off all of a sudden?
何だよ？
急に食いついてきやがって
うっせえ！
Shut up!
It would've caused me a little trouble, so I didn't reveal myself as a woman.
多少 面倒そうだから
女とは明かさない　その程度だ
That's all.
よっぽど自信があるんだな
自分の腕に
You sure have a lot of self-confidence...
In your own skill.
（羌瘣）
私より強い人間は この世にいない
There is no human stronger than me in this world.
こら てめえ！
そりゃ言い過ぎだろう！
Hey, you! Now you're going too far!
Would you like to see for yourself?
確かめてみるか？
（信）えっ…
フッ…
しかし ちょっとホッとしたぜ
But, I'm a little relieved.
I thought you were a cold guy who didn't like other people.
お前 他人には興味ない
冷たいヤツかと思ってたが
But it looks like that wasn't really it.
ホントは そうじゃなかったんだな
何だ？ それは
What.. do you mean by that?
なんか よく分かんねえが
わざわざ俺に会いに来てくれてよ
I don't totally get it, but you went out of your way to come see me.
ハハハッ…
（羌瘣）それは…
That was...
お前とは これからも
一緒にやりてえと思ってたんだ
I was thinkin' I'd like to continue fighting together with you.
仲間だもんな！
We're comrades, right?!
Stop!
やめろ！
（信･貂）えっ？
I did not join the fighting for a reason like that.
そんなつもりで
戦いに加わったわけじゃない
目的の途中に偶然 戦いがあった
それだけのことだ
It was just a coincidental fight on my way to my goal.
That's all.
Goal?
目的？
I have no interest in "being together" or "comrades".
“一緒に”とか “仲間”とか
そんなことには興味ない
（信）お前の目的って何なんだ？
Then what is your goal?
女のお前が あそこまで強いのは
なんでなんだ？
And how did a woman become that strong?!
俺も知りたい！ 教えてくれよ
（信）貂…
I wanna know, too!
Please, tell me!
Diao?
I want to become strong!
俺も強くなりたいんだ
俺も お前と同じ…
Like you...
Wh-What're you doing?!
（信）何すんだ てめえ！
（羌瘣）ふざけるな
Stop messing around!
そもそも 生まれた世界が全く違う
The worlds we were born in are completely different.
“知りたい”だの “教えろ”だの
甘く見るヤツには ヘドが出る
People who say things like "I want to know" and "Tell me"...
are taking it so lightly, it makes me sick.
私が生きている理由は
ひとつしかない
I have only one reason for living.
“蚩尤(しゆう)”として生まれたことが
私の運命を決めたんだ
Born as a Chi You, my fate was sealed.
蚩尤？
Chi You?
（羌瘣）歴史の影に
生き続けてきた暗殺者集団
A band of assassins that have survived in the shadows of history.
今では そう言われている一族だ
That is what our clan is now described as.
（バア）
汝(なんじ)ら全員 我らが幼虫の糧に…
You will all be food for our larvae...
（山賊Ａ）何言ってやがんだ？
このばあさんは
What're you talkin' about, you old bat?
（山賊Ｂ）
迷い込んだ先が悪かったな
You picked a bad place to get lost in.
None 'a you guys are gettin' outta here alive.
（山賊Ｃ）
お前ら全員 生きちゃ帰れねえぜ
What? Do you not recognize the Chi You?
（バア）
汝ら 蚩尤を知らぬと見える
Chi You?
（山賊Ａ）蚩尤？
The sword was not originally something to cut people down with.
剣とは元来 人を斬る物にあらず
In ancient times, it was born as a sacred treasure for worshiping the heavens.
太古の世 天を祭る神器として
生まれし物なり
The maidens that dance with swords are possessed with the power of the gods...
その剣に
神がかりの力を宿して舞う巫女(みこ)
They are the Chi You.
それが蚩尤じゃ
（山賊Ｂ）さっぱり分かんねえ
それが何だってんだ？
I haven't got a clue what you're talking about.
So what?
（バア）
蚩尤は 舞いながら 神の力で斬る
The Chi You dance as they cut down their foes with the power of the gods.
人間の力など 到底 及ばぬ
Far beyond the strength of mere humans.
（山賊Ｃ）ああ そうかい
Oh, is that right?
Okay, okay, gotcha, granny.
（山賊Ａ）
よしよし　分かったよ ばあさん
Dance,
（バア）舞え！ 我らが羌族の娘
our daughters of the Qiang Tribe, Xiang, Lei.
象(しょう)！ 瘣！
（山賊Ａ）何だ？ そりゃ
踊りで許しを請おうって…
What's that supposed to be?
Are you begging us for forgiveness with a dance?
The Chi You are split into clans and live among the mountains.
（羌瘣）蚩尤は
氏族ごとに分かれて 山々に点在し
素質ある者には
幼いころから修練を積ませて
Those with talents are trained from early childhood
to produce warriors to take on the name of Chi You.
蚩尤の名を継ぐ者を輩出させる
The clans place all value on that alone.
全氏族が
そのことだけに全てを懸ける
それが掟(おきて)だ
That is our law.
When I turned 13, I had part of deciding the new Chi You.
私が13になった年 新たな蚩尤を
決めねばならなくなった
19ある氏族から
２人ずつが選ばれる
Two are chosen from each of the 19 clans.
羌族からは 私と
姉妹同然に育った象姉が選ばれた
My sister, Xiang, whom had been raised the same way as me,
as well as myself were chosen from the Qiang Clan.
To win the name of Chi You, the candidates had to fight each other
候補者たちは 蚩尤の名を巡って
最後の１人になるまで
戦わねばならない
until only one remained.
Only one!
最後の１人になるまで
それは
“祭(さい)”と呼ばれる一族の掟だった
That was a law of our family called "festival".
（象）あれは幽族(ゆうぞく)の連(れん)
That is Lian of the You Clan.
（象）こっちは蛾族(がぞく)の経(きょう)
This one is Jing of the Eh Tribe.
（象）２人とも かなりやる
Both are considerably skilled.
心配ないよ
あした 生き残るのは象姉だ
Don't worry.
The survivor of tomorrow will be you, Big Sister Xiang.
（象）だとしたら
瘣は あした 死ぬってことだよ？
In that case, you will be dead tomorrow, Qiang.
しかも
この私に殺されるかもしれない
And you might even be killed by me.
それなら それで かまわないよ
If that happened, I wouldn't mind it.
We were taught since we were little that our lives would last until the festival.
小さなころから
“祭までの命”と教えられてきたし
私はイヤだ
（羌瘣）えっ？
I... don't like it.
Dying at just 15 years old...
たった15で死ぬなんて…
（象）まだまだ
やりたいことが山ほどある
There are still mountains of things I want to do.
平地にある国ってのも見てみたいし
そこに住む人間も見てみたい
I want to see the "states" of the flatlands
and the humans that live there.
I'd like to have a child someday.
いつかは子供を産んでみたいし
何より その前に
男のぬくもりも知ってみたい
And before that, I'd at least like to know the warmth of a man...
（象）ハハハッ… あんたには
まだ ちょっと早かったね
That might be a little early for you.
（象）あした
ホントは瘣にも死んでほしくない
Honestly, I don't want you to die tomorrow, either, Lei.
You need to survive and take on the name of Chi You
生き延びて 蚩尤の名を継いで
外の世界をたくさん知ってほしい
and learn all about the outside world.
（羌瘣）ムリだよ
There's no way.
同じ種族でも
手を組むことは禁止で
Even among the same clan, to team up is forbidden.
残るのは１人だけ
Only one will remain...
そういう掟だもん
（象）だからさ…
That is the law.
That's why,
あしたは お互い 自分のために
戦わなくちゃいけないんだ
tomorrow, we have to fight for ourselves!
Even if you and I end up fighting each other!
たとえ
私とあんたが戦うことになっても
絶対に遠慮するんじゃないよ 瘣
No matter what, don't hold back, Lei!
分かってる
I understand.
Lu Sui... Make sure you protect Lei tomorrow.
（象）緑穂(りょくすい)…
あしたは しっかり瘣を守るんだぞ
（羌瘣）象姉…
Big Sister Xiang...
Lei...
瘣… あんたのこと
ホントの妹のように思ってた
I've always thought of you as a little sister.
私もだよ 象姉
Me, too...
Big Sister Xiang.
There are 36 candidates besides Big Sister Xiang and me.
（羌瘣）
私と象姉以外の候補者は36人
I'll go all-out as soon as the festival begins.
祭の開始と同時に 全開でいく
強そうなヤツから
10人も斬れば十分だ
If I can cut down ten strong-looking ones, that'll be plenty...
The rest will be up to Big Sister Xiang...
あとは 象姉が やってくれる
そして 象姉は
蚩尤になって 外の世界に…
Then Big Sister Xiang will become Chi You and venture to the outside world...
Got it, Lu Sui? That's what I've decided.
いいんだ 緑穂
そう決めていたんだ
Let's go to sleep.
もう眠ろう　あしたは早い
We're getting up early tomorrow.
夕方？
Eve...ning...?
I overslept?!
寝過ごした？
バカな… ありえない！
That can't be! It's impossible!
何かあった…
Something happened!
Incense?!
香？ 眠らされた！
I was put to sleep?!
誰に…
By whom?!
象姉？
Big Sister Xiang?!
祭は… 祭は どうなった？
The festival...
What happened with the festival?!
Big Sister Xiang... What happened to her...?!
象姉は…
象姉…
Big Sister Xiang...
Big Sister Xiang.
象姉…
Big Sister Xiang!
象姉！
いない… 象姉は いない
She's not here... Big Sister Xiang isn't here!
She's not!
いない！ 象姉 勝ち残った…
Big Sister Xiang survi...ved!
（羌瘣）勘違いするな
象姉は弱かったわけじゃない
Don't misunderstand.
Big Sister Xiang was not weak.
あの中では 群を抜いて強かった
（貂）それじゃ なんで…
Her strength was exemplary.
Then how...?
（羌瘣）バア… なぜだ？
なぜ 象姉が こんな…
Elder... How?
How did this happen to Big Sister Xiang...?
象姉が負ける相手なんて
１人もいなかったのに
There's no opponent that could defeat Big Sister Xiang!
象は狙われていたんじゃ 最初から
Xiang was targeted from the outset.
ハッ… 狙われていた？
Targeted?
As soon as the battle started, she was immediately ambushed by a large group.
（バア）象は 開始と同時に
大勢から一斉に攻撃を受けた
（長老）では 掟に従い 祭を行う
And now, in accordance to our laws, the festival will commence.
（長老）始め！
Begin!
（連）フッ… 小娘が
Hmph... That girl...
（バア）幽族の連が見守る中でな
And Lian of the You Clan oversaw it.
（羌瘣）バカな… ありえない！
No! That can't be!
In the festival, not even two members of the same clan are allowed to fight in an alliance!
祭では たとえ同族の２人でも
手を組んで戦ってはならない
それが掟だ！ そうだろう？
That's the law!
Isn't it?!
Lei,
瘣！ お前と象の力は
明らかに ぬきんでていた
Xiang's and your power were clearly extraordinary.
全氏族の長(おさ)たちも認めていた
じゃから 黙認された
The chiefs of the other tribes all recognized it.
So they tacitly condoned this.
（バア）
ほかの連中が手を組むことも
Both, that the others all joined forces, and that you did not participate.
お前の不参加も
（羌瘣）黙認？
Condoned?
Wait a minute...
ちょっと待て… 掟は？
What about that law?
Is the law not absolute?!
掟は絶対ではないのか？
そんなに軽いものだったのか？
Was it really something that insignificant?!
Elder!
（羌瘣）バア！
だったら…
だったら なんで こんなことを…
Then how... How did this happen?!
Why did Big Sister Xiang have to die?!
なんで象姉は
死ななくちゃならなかったんだ？
（長老）何をしている？ 羌長(おさ)
そやつは既に死人(しびと)だぞ
What is this you're saying, Qiang Chief?
She is already a corpse.
自決しろ 羌の小娘
祭の勝者は決した
Kill yourself, Qiang girl.
The winner of the festival has been decided.
敗者は１人残らず死すべし
All losers must die!
It is a law of the Chi You that has gone unbroken these last thousand years!
それが連綿と連なる蚩尤の
1,000年の掟だ
（羌瘣）
バカにしているのか？ 貴様ら
Do you take me for a fool?
You bastards?
I was sick of hearing about thousand year long laws.
（羌瘣）
1,000年の掟が聞いてあきれる
年寄りたちを皆殺しにして
自分も死のうかと考えたが
I thought about killing all of the elders and then myself,
but I stopped short of that.
思いとどめた
There is one thing I must do before I die.
死ぬ前に １つだけ
やらねばならないことがある
幽族の連とかってヤツか？
That Lian from the You Clan, or whatever, right?
そうだ　あいつだけは…
Yes. She is the one that I...
フフフッ… 眠れ
Go to sleep.
She plotted to form a secret alliance and killed Big Sister Xiang,
裏で手組みを謀り
象姉を殺したあいつが―
結局 新たな蚩尤となり
里の外へ出た
and in the end became the new Chi You and left the village...
She is the one I can never forgive!
ヤツだけは絶対に許さない！
I lost Big Sister Xiang and threw away the Chi You village.
象姉を失い 蚩尤の里も捨てた
Now, my only reason for living is to kill that woman.
今の私の命は
あの女を殺すためだけにあるんだ
（貂）悔しいよな
（信）えっ？
That must be mortifying...
（貂）いいかげんな掟に
振り回されたことも
To be manipulated by silly laws,
and for Big Sister Xiang to be killed by such cowardly tactics...
卑劣な手で象姉が殺されたことも
殺したヤツが蚩尤になって―
The one who killed her became Chi You
のうのうと生きてることも
そうだけど
and is living a carefree life now.
But more than anything...
何より…
大事な人が殺されたときに
その場にいられなかったなんて…
to not have been there when someone very dear to you was killed.
Why do you say that?
なぜ そう思う？
俺は それが いちばん怖いから
That's what I'm afraid of the most.
貂…
Diao...
（信）すっかり夜になっちまったな
泊まってっていいぞ 羌瘣
Man, it really got late.
You can stay here if you want, Qiang Lei.
（羌瘣）そうだな
All right.
（信）どうした？
What's up?
（貂）なんか寝つけねえや
ちょっと風に当たってくる
I kinda can't sleep.
I'm gonna go get some fresh air.
黒卑村(こくひむら)にいたときは―
When I lived in Heibei Village,
I thought about how I could sneak away from there every day.
毎日 どうやったら
抜け出せるかばかり考えてた
でも 信や政(せい)たちと出会って
王都奪還の戦いに巻き込まれて…
But then I met Xin, Zheng and the others
and got wrapped up in the battle to retake the capital.
I don't really understand it,
（貂）何だか分かんねえけど
俺は ときめいてた
but I've been enjoying it.
Even though it seems like we could die every day...
いつ死ぬかも
分かんねえ毎日だったのに
ちょっと落ち着いて
あれこれ考えてみて
when I calm down and think about things,
somehow, I understand it.
なんとなく分かったぜ
信… 多分 お前と一緒にいたからだ
Xin, it's probably because I've been with you.
２人で暮らし始めて
これといって 何もないけど
I haven't said anything about it since we started living together,
幸せな時間が やって来た
but I've been really happy.
俺にとっては初めての楽しい毎日
The first fun days I've ever had...
それが ずっと続くと思ってた
I thought they would keep going forever.
But I was wrong.
だけど 違った
信は どんどん前に進む
Xin keep moving forward.
And it's not just him.
信だけじゃない
政も 壁(へき)も 昌文君(しょうぶんくん)も…
Zheng, Bi, and Changwenjun are, too...
Everyone is moving forward, risking their lives.
みんな 命懸けで前に進んでいる
The moment I realized it, I was all alone facing the wrong direction, sitting in the wrong place.
気がついたら １人だけ―
違うほうを向いて
違う所に座ってた
This is just the same as before.
これじゃ 前と同じだ
俺 どうすりゃいいんだよ？
What am I supposed to do?
I can't sleep!
寝られん！
ジロジロ見るな 暑苦しい
Quit staring at me like that. It's suffocating.
ヘヘッ… 悪い悪い
Sorry, sorry.
けど お前 よく見ると
ホントかわいい顔してんだな
But getting a good look at you, you've really got a cute face.
Are you an idiot?
アホか
（信）俺も
兄弟同然の漂(ひょう)ってヤツを殺された
I had someone, who was like a sibling to me, that was killed too, his name is Piao.
To me, that guy was...
そいつは 俺にとって…
話さなくていい
（信）えっ？
You don't need to tell me.
なんとなく聞いていた
尾平(びへい)たちと話しているのを
I heard about it
from talking with Wei Ping and the others.
そっか　じゃ いいや
Oh, then fine.
お前の話だけ聞いたんじゃ
悪いような気がしてよ
I just kinda felt bad only listening to your story.
信…
（信）うん？
Xin...
お前… 変なヤツだな
You're... a strange person.
Huh?! What's with you all of a sudden?!
はぁ？ 何だよ？ 急に
だから 私も変だ
（信）えっ？
So I'm strange, too.
お前は運が良かっただけだぞ
You were just lucky.
In that battle against Wei,
この間の魏(ぎ)との戦いでも―
お前より腕の立つヤツは
ゴロゴロいた
the people stronger than you were scattered all over.
（信）分かってるよ …んなこと
I know that.
I thought I would be getting a lot of experience with that battle.
今回の戦で
いろんな経験をして 思ったんだ
勢いとか気持ちだけで突っ走ったら
ホントの戦いには勝てねえってな
If you just rush in on momentum and emotion
you can't win a real fight.
その辺のことは
ちゃんと考えてある
Don't worry, I've been... thinking about all that.
Good, then.
（羌瘣）なら いい
So what're you gonna do next?
（信）
お前は これから どうするんだ？
（羌瘣）１人で魏を目指す
I'm going to head for Wei alone.
私には…
That's... all I have.
それしかない
じゃ 終わったら 速攻で帰ってこい
Well, when that's over, make sure you hurry back!
仇討(あだう)ち以外 何もねえとか
言ってたが そんなのは大ウソだ
You said you've got nothin' besides getting revenge,
but that must be a big lie.
そんなヤツが あの激しい合戦の中
Somebody like that would not be risking their life for those around them in a big battle.
周りのために
体張ったりするかってんだ
いいか？ 羌瘣
Understand, Qiang Lei?
お前は
同じ伍で一緒に戦った仲間として
As a comrade who fought in the same Wu as me,
I've counted you as one of the people in my hundred man unit a while ago!
とっくに 俺の百人隊の
頭数に入ってんだからな
So make sure you get your ass back here by the next war.
だから 次の戦までに
絶対 戻ってこいよ　分かったな？
Got it?
Don't decide that on your own.
（羌瘣）勝手に入れるな
うるせえ！ 返事は？
Cut that out! What's your answer?!
I'll think about it.
考えとく
（信）なっ…
（信）まあいいや
Aw, fine.
I'll be waiting the whole time, okay?
ず～っと待ってっからな
Qiang Lei, you're glad you joined that war, aren't you?
羌瘣 お前
あの戦に参加して良かっただろう
（羌瘣）そうだな
（信）じゃ 絶対 帰ってこいよ！
Yeah, I guess.
Then be damn sure you come back!
（羌瘣）しつこい
You're so persistent.
Oh, you're up?
あっ 起きたか
あいつ 行ったか
（貂）ああ… ほら 食うぞ 朝メシ
So she... left, huh?
Yeah.
Hey, let's eat breakfast!
信 ちょっと聞け
（信）うん？ 何だ？
Xin, listen for a sec.
Hm? What?
俺の野望を覚えてるか？
Do you remember my ambition?
超大金持ちになって
一生 豪遊して暮らすことだ
To become super-rich and live the rest of my life enjoying myself.
ああ！ そういや
んなこと言ってたな お前
Oh, right. You did say somethin' like that, right?
I haven't got the least bit of interest in living in this cheap-ass broken down shack.
こんな しみったれたボロ小屋で
セコセコやってく気は毛頭ない
分かってるよ　すぐ俺が出世して
ド～ンと でかい屋敷を…
I know.
I'm gonna make it big soon and we'll have a giant mansion.
お前をアテにしようとも思ったが
それは やめた
I thought I'd rely on you for it,
but I'm not doing that anymore!
お前 いつ死ぬか分からんしな
（信）なんだよ それ…
I've got no idea when you might die.
Wh-What's with that attitude?
だから 俺も戦場に出て―
That's why I've decided to head to the battlefield, too, and earn some big money.
大金を稼ぐことにした
（信）えっ？
You're gonna fight?
戦うってのか？ お前
腕っぷしじゃ
どうにもできねえのは分かってる
I know I can't do anything about my physical strength!
I'm not sure about it... but...
でも 分かんねえけど…
there's got to be something I can do!
きっと何か
俺にできることがあると思うんだ
だから…
（信）うん？
So...
お前 また戦が始まったら
行くんだろう？
You're going to leave when a new war starts, right?
行く
Yeah.
When that happens, I'm leaving, too.
そのとき 俺も ここを出るよ
俺の場所を見つけるために
So I can find where I belong.
Is that right?
そうか
We may not see each other for a while,
しばらく会えないかもしれないけど
絶対 戻ってくるから
but I'll definitely come back.
To where you are.
お前のとこに
フッ… 待ってるぞ
（貂）フフフッ…
I'll be waiting!
All right!
（信）しゃー！
今日も張り切っていくか！
Let's get fired up today, too!
（貂）おう！ じゃ 片づけ手伝え
Right!
Then, help clean up!
（信）それは お前がやれよ
（貂）…んだと？
Yeah, you do that.
What?!
（貂）お前も たまには やれよ
（信）言っただろうが
You've gotta do it once in a while, too!
Didn' I tell you?
俺は メシ作んのも 片づけんのも
ド下手だって
I'm shit at making food and cleaning up!
だから 食うの専門なんだよ
（貂）勝手に決めんな こら！
So all I'm gonna do is eat!
And who decided that, you moron?!
michi wa tsuzuku yume wo oimotome
路は続く　夢を追い求め
The path goes on, chasing after a dream.
nozomu saki ni kimi no ashita wa aru no?
望む先に　君の明日はあるの？
Will your tomorrow be at the place my hopes lead?
kizutsuite kokoro mo mada kawaku nara
傷ついて　心もまだ渇くなら
If I get hurt and my heart is still thirsty,
koko e kite nando demo utau kara
ここへ来て何度でも歌うから
I'll come here and sing as many times as it takes.
owari naki tatakai no naka de
終わりなき戦いの中で
In this endless battle
kimi wa tsuyoku kawaru
君は強く変わる
You change to become stronger.
kono sora wo kirisaita ikazuchi wa kimi
この空を切り裂いた　雷は君
The lightning that cut apart this sky is you.
osore wo koete tachimukau hikari no ya hashiridasu
恐れを超えて立ち向かう　光の矢　走りだす
The arrow of light that overcomes fear faces forward and shoots forth.
tsukamu sadame shinjitsuzukeru no...
掴む　運命　信じ続けるの…
I'll grab onto the destiny I've always believed in...
～♪
Preview
（信）俺は 天下の大将軍に
修行をつけてほしいんだ
In order to be greatest general under the heavens,
I've gotta train!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）未来への１歩
The path to the future.
For the path that you seek,
目指すべき道のため
更なる進化を求める
seek further evolution!
A New Trial
End
次回 “新たなる試練”
Next time,